(サクラ)いた。
(カカシ)やっぱりここか。
There they are!
It figures they'd be here.
(ナルト)ありがとう サクラちゃん。
Thanks, Sakura.
(サスケ)サクラ 俺は…。
Sakura…
Never mind me…
今は黙って。 集中するから。
Stay quiet now.
I need to concentrate.
すまなかった。
I'm sorry…
すまなかったって… なにが？
Sorry? For what?
今までの…。
For everything…
You should be.
ほんとよ…。
まったく。
Really...you…
しゃーんなろーよ… バカ。
damn…
idiot!
やっと戻ったね。
He's finally back.
＜ナルト このときの俺は→
Naruto…
I've been thinking about
what you once said to me.
あの お前の言葉を
思い出していた。
俺といるとき 兄弟がいるのは
こんな感じなのかと思うと…＞
When we were together,
you wondered if it was
how having a brother would feel…
＜ その感覚が このとき
やっとわかったんだ＞
Now, finally…
I think I know what you meant.
＜父や母 それに兄弟だった
イタチの苦しみや思いが→
I felt how my mother, father,
and brother Itachi suffered.
俺に伝わってきたのと
同じように＞
In that same way…
Naruto…
＜今は ナルト…
お前の苦しみや思いが→
I'm sure I will start to feel your pain
and your emotions…
同じように伝わってくるだろうと。
お前は 決して俺を切らず ずっと
俺の心に近づいてきてくれた＞
You never cut me off.
You always kept me in your thoughts.
(ヒナタ)ナルト君…。
Naruto…
SHIKAKU NARA
INOICHI YAMANAKA
＜俺に 憎しみをぶつけてきても
おかしくなかったはずなのに→
You'd have been justified if
you'd come at me with hatred…
Instead, you always called me
your friend.
お前は ずっと
俺のことを友だと言った＞
NEJI HYUGA
＜俺は その思いすら
切ろうとしたってのに＞
And I tried to betray
even those feelings…
(ゲンマ)ですから 里の方針で
ナルトへの接見は→
As I explained,
it's the village policy.
Only those authorized are allowed
at the interview.
関係者以外
お断りしておりますので→
All others, please leave!
どうか お引き取りください！
What? Do you know
how far I traveled?
おい！ なんだよ…
遠路はるばる来たんだぞ!!
Let us see him, just once!
ひと目でいいから会わせろ！
そうだ そうだ！
– Yeah!
(コテツ)ですから
これは 里の方針で…。
It's the village policy…
(３人)ナルトさんに会わせろ！
– Let us see Naruto!
(イズモ)ちょっと！
危ないですから 押さないで。
Please don't push! It's dangerous.
(綱手)これで とりあえず
引き継ぎは全部だ。
This should take care
of the successorship.
はぁ… すごい量ですね。
It's a lot of paper.
まぁな。 六代目火影 就任
おめでとう カカシ。
Yeah…
Anyway, congratulations on becoming
the Sixth Hokage, Kakashi.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
I just wonder…
Can I do this?
でも… 私に務まりますかね？
まぁ なんとかなるだろう。
私でも なんとかなったしな。
You'll manage. After all, I did.
I'll do my best.
頑張ってみます。
(シズネ)失礼します。
Excuse me.
(シズネ)報告
雷影様ご一行に続いて→
Status report:
The Raikage's entourage and
the Kazekage's entourage
have arrived.
風影様ご一行も
お見えになられました。
May I escort them to Naruto, too?
ナルト君のもとへ
案内しても かまいませんか？
You may.
(２人)あぁ。
フフッ…。
それと…。
Further…
(シカマル)お願いがあります。
I have a request.
(カカシ)なるほど。 シカマル…
お前のもくろみは わかった。
I see, Shikamaru.
I understand your intentions.
(シカマル)俺自身も 将来を見すえて
経験値を上げておきたいっすから。
I want to get some experience
and improve my prospects too.
あとは あいつか。
All that's left is him.
(綱手)よそからの訪問者も
絶えんようだし→
A ton of visitors are asking about him.
たいした人気者だ！
Suddenly he's Mr. Popular.
大丈夫です。 有頂天に溺れる隙は
与えませんから。
That's all right.
He's not the type to get carried away.
Hey! Gaara!
おっ！ 我愛羅。
(我愛羅)ナルト…。
Naruto…
お前に また救われたな。
You…saved me yet again.
(エー)我々もだ。
And us.
(カンクロウ)で… ケガの具合は？
How's your wound?
まぁ 見てのとおりだ。
It's about what you'd guess.
大丈夫とは言えねえけど。
Can't say I'm in the best shape.
(テマリ)それで
その腕は どうなるんだ？
Then, what'll you do about that arm?
あぁ 綱手のばあちゃんの話だと→
Oh, Grandma Tsunade said
something about
harvesting cells from Hashirama,
the First Hokage, or whatever.
なんか 初代火影の柱間細胞を
培養だか なんだかで→
俺の細胞と掛け合わせるらしい。
She's gonna fuse them with mine,
I suppose?
なんのことか
よく わかんねえけど。
I don't really understand.
また 元どおりになるのか？
あぁ たぶんな。
Will it be as good as new?
Yeah! I think.
今日は
その検査のためだけに来てんだ。
I'm here today so they can check.
そうか…。
I see…
Naruto is the Ninja World's sun!
His right hand's a precious companion!
♪♪(キラービー)「ナルトは忍世界の太陽」
♪♪「右腕 大事な相棒」
Losing it is devastation! Yay!
♪♪「それをなくすは 敗北 イエー」
♪♪「取り戻すための対応」
So to get it back intact!
Use Hashirama's cells, in fact.
♪♪「柱間細胞 培養」
It'll be as good as new, Jack! Yay!
♪♪「元に戻るは 最高。 アッ！ イエー」
アハハハハ！
やつは 今 どうしている？
What's he up to?
それについては
あんま話したくねえな…。
I really don't wanna say much.
口止めもされてっし。
SEAL
I promised I wouldn't.
そうか…。
I see.
(リー)せ… 先生！
S-Sensei!
(ガイ)泣くな リー。
Don't cry, Lee!
若く
まぶしい青春は終わろうとも→
Even if the bright days of youth end here,
there is still a future for me!
俺には まだ先がある。
The sun that shines bright!
ギラギラ輝く太陽
モンモンとうだる暑さ。
The sweltering heat!
紅く燃えたぎる→
The red-hot days of
summer are here!
円熟の朱夏の季節の到来だ！
《あっ 痛い…》
O-Oww…
うお～！ ガイ先生
感動です！
Guy Sensei!
I'm inspired!
What a brilliant way of thinking!
なんて
すばらしい考え方でしょう！
《テンテン : うざ…》
Oh yuck…
NINJA ACADEMY
Shikamaru…
シカマル お前 火影の側近補佐に
就いたんだって？
I hear you're
the Hokage's personal assistant.
まあな。
俺も前に進まねえとな。
Well, yeah.
I have to keep moving forward too.
で なんでアカデミーに俺を？
So why'd you ask me to
come to the Academy?
え？ イルカ先生と カカシ先生。
Iruka Sensei? And Kakashi Sensei?
先生っていうか火影な。
More like Lord Hokage now.
えっ ええ～！
いつの間に！?
Huh?! When did that—?!
今朝 内々の伝達あったろ。
You must have seen all the messages
that came in this morning.
知らなかった～。
I had no idea…
Don't worry about it.
まあ いいけどよ。
え～と じゃあ
何て呼べばいいんだ？
So what do I call you?
カカシ火影？
火影カカシティーチャーとか？
Kakashi Hokage?
Hokage Kakashi Teacher?
まあ それは
後で決めてもらうとして。
Well, let's decide that later.
ナルト。
Naruto!
お前 中忍試験すら
受けてなかったな。
You never got to take
the Chunin Exam, right?
うん。
うずまきナルト。
No…
Naruto Uzumaki!
六代目火影の名の下に→
I, the Sixth Hokage, hereby grant you
お前を木ノ葉隠れの里
上忍に任命する。
the rank of Jonin of
the Village Hidden in the Leaves!
と言いたいところなんだが→
…is what I'd like to tell you.
But there's something
you must complete before that.
そのためには
クリアしなきゃならんことがある。
(イルカ)今のお前に必要な教材だ。
The educational materials
you'll be needing.
You mean…?
これって…。
ま いわゆる勉強だ。
Yes, you have study.
べ 勉強だと～
イヤだ～！
Study?!
No way!
ヤダ ヤダ ヤダ！
No way, no way!
勉強するくれえなら
下忍のままでいいってばよ！
If I'm gonna have to study,
I'll just stay a genin!
(カカシ)待て ナルト。
Hold on, Naruto.
(木ノ葉丸)火影までの道程に
近道なんてないぞ コレ！
There's no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
Got it?!
ナルト お前の忍としての実力は→
Naruto…
I don't have to tell you
もはや
俺が語るまでもないだろう。
that your skill as a shinobi
is second to none.
だが この先
火影を目指すなら→
However, if your goal is
to become the Hokage…
まずは人の上に立ち→
You must learn how to stand
above others and lead them.
導くことを
学ばなければならない。
それに お前は頭が回るし→
You catch on fast,
and for most things,
たいていの知略は
シカマルがサポートしてくれるだろうが→
Shikamaru will support you
with his resourcefulness.
それでも最低限の知識
教養は必要だ。
Still, a minimum of learning
and knowledge is essential.
俺たち
火影を目指すライバルだろう コレ。
We're rivals who both aim to
become Hokage, right?!
THE HISTORY OF SHINOBI
VOLUME 1
ああ。
頑張ったな ナルト。
You really dug in, Naruto.
あと２年もすれば
上忍なれるぞ。
Two more years,
and you can become a jonin.
なげえ～…。
So long…
よし 今日は終わりにして
ラーメンでも食いに行くか。
Okay, let's call it a day
and go grab some ramen.
やった～！
Yes!
NINJA ACADEMY
さ～てと トッピングは
何にしようかなっと。
NINJA ACADEMY
Now what toppings should I choose?
フフ こらこら
調子に乗るなよ。
Hey, don't get carried away.
イルカ先生のおかげだ。
ええ？
It's all thanks to you, Iruka Sensei.
Huh?
あの日のこと 覚えてる？
Do you remember that day?
ああ。
あのとき 先生→
Hmm?
That night, Sensei…
俺のことを
認めてくれただろう？
You accepted me.
初めてだったんだ。
It was the first time ever.
だから 今の俺があるんだ。
That's why I'm here today.
もし誰からも
認めてもらえねえで→
If no one acknowledged me
and I stayed the way I was…
あのままだったら→
Maybe I would've resented the village
and everyone in it, and gone wild.
里や みんなを恨んで
ムチャクチャになってたかもしんねえ。
But your words
that night changed me.
でも あのとき 先生の言葉で
俺は変われたんだ。
((けど ナルトは違う。
But Naruto is different.
あいつは
あいつは この俺が認めた→
He's…
He's an exceptional student
and I acknowledge him!
優秀な生徒だ。
He is…
(あいつは 木ノ葉隠れの里の
うずまきナルトだ))
Naruto Uzumaki of the Hidden Leaf!
ありがとう イルカ先生。
Thank you, Iruka Sensei.
That…that does it!
しかたないな。
今日は奮発 フルトッピングでいいぞ。
Today, you can have
all the toppings you want!
やった～！
Awright!
サスケ。
Sasuke…
(カカシ)まっ はっきり言って
本来ならお前は→
I'll be blunt.
By rights, you should be
in prison right now.
強制的に
投獄される身だったから→
お前の望みが聞き入れられ
今までの行為が免責されたのは→
But we have heard your plea and
all your actions up to now
have been pardoned.
無限月読解術による功績が
大きいってことだったけどさ→
Breaking the jutsu
for the Infinite Tsukuyomi
played a big part in the decision.
六代目火影が俺になったことや→
As well as the fact that I happened
to become the Sixth Hokage,
この戦争終結の立役者になった
ナルトの嘆願によるところが→
and that Naruto,
the key figure in ending the war,
testified on your behalf.
大きかったこと 忘れないように。
Don't forget that.
これからは あまりムチャしないでよ。
And please don't get too reckless.
俺の責任になっちゃうから。
Otherwise, I'll be held responsible.
ああ すまない。
Understood. Thank you.
どうしても行っちゃうの？
Must you go?
綱手様が柱間様の細胞で
造った義手も もう少しで…。
The artificial arm that
Lady Tsunade is creating
from Lord Hashirama's cells will soon…
今の俺なら この忍界が→
I need time to understand
my feelings.
この世界が どう見えるのか→
How I should view the shinobi world,
this world.
知りたいんだ。
今まで見逃してきたことも
見えそうな気がする。
Perhaps I'll be able to see things
I couldn't see before.
このままでなければ見えない
何かが…。
Things that can't be seen
unless I do this.
それに 気になってることも
あるしな。
Also, there's something
I'm worried about.
私も… ついていくって言ったら？
What if I said…I'd go with you?
罪を償う旅でもある。
This is a trip to atone for my sins.
お前は俺の罪とは関係ない。
My sins have
nothing to do with you.
関係ないか…。
Nothing to do with me…?
また今度な。
Maybe next time.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
お前は見送りには
来ないと思ったが。
I didn't think
you'd come to see me off.
ん。
Here.
お前 まだこんなもん。
You kept that thing?
＜片腕を失ってまで
俺を止めてくれた。
You sacrificed your arm to stop me.
お前のおかげで俺は救われた。
Thanks to you, I found salvation.
いがみ合ってた
ちっぽけな俺たちが→
Once, all we did was clash
with each other.
今は互いの心を
痛み合うことができる。
But now, we share each other's pain.
そして 旅を通して
世界を見てこう思った。
After all my travels
through the world,
I came to the conclusion
このことは俺たちだけじゃなく→
that this sharing of pain
もっと大きなものにも
言えることなのかもしれないと。
can perhaps be applied to something
much bigger than just us.
だが お前のようには
なかなかできるものじゃない。
But I can't do things like you.
そう簡単にはいかないだろう。
Things don't go that smoothly,
俺たち自身がそうだったように→
as you and I know more than anyone…
大きなものなら なおさらな＞
The bigger something is, the harder.
これを返す。
I'm returning this.
お前との本当の勝負まで…。
I'll hang on to it…
取っておいてやるよ。
…until our real match.
＜ それは祈りにも似た思いだ。
This idea is almost a prayer.
それでも それができるまで
耐え忍んでいく。
To keep enduring, no matter what,
until things come
その様を任された者たち。
それが俺たち 忍者なのかもな＞
＜ヒルゼン : 昔 妖狐ありけり。
その狐 九つの尾あり。
狐 封印されし忍の童→
これと長きにわたり 寄り添いて→
いつしか 友となりけり。
新たな厄災 十尾復活せしが→
忍の童 忍の者となり→
妖狐と忍の輩 一丸となりて→
これを封印せしめる。
妖狐封印 忍の者→
四代目火影の子にして
名をうずまきナルトと申す＞